<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Supaaasuge&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://supaaasuge.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Supaaasuge&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://supaaasuge.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Board Light - HackTheBox Writeup (Easy)</title>
      <link>https://supaaasuge.github.io/posts/board-light-htb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://supaaasuge.github.io/posts/board-light-htb/</guid>
      <description>Machine Summary In this Hack The Box machine, I start of with basic Nmap enumeration. Then move on to directory enumeration and vhost enumeration using gobuster and ffuf. From here, we find an endpoint running Dollibarr v17.0.0 that is vulnerable to CVE-2023-30253. We are able to leverage this to get a reverse shell on the machine and get an initial foothold. From here, we find a password for the user larissa and are able to use these credentials to log in via SSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antique - HTB Writeup</title>
      <link>https://supaaasuge.github.io/posts/antique-htb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://supaaasuge.github.io/posts/antique-htb/</guid>
      <description>Enumeration Starting off, I ran a nmap TCP scan on all ports. The only open port from this was 23(Telnet), so I then decided to try a UDP scan (-sU), in which port 161(SNMP) was found.
From here, I went ahead and connected to port 23 using telnet. HP JetDirect was the live service for this port, I am going to go ahead and search google for any exploits for HP JetDirect</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bizness - HTB Writeup</title>
      <link>https://supaaasuge.github.io/posts/bizness-htb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://supaaasuge.github.io/posts/bizness-htb/</guid>
      <description>Bizness is a Easy Linux machine initially released on January 6th, 2024. As usual, I start with basic enumeration using Nmap; and from there used dirsearch for directory enumeration. From directory enumeration we find a login page running Apache OFBiz. This version of Apache OFBiz is vulnerable to an authentication bypass vulnerability CVE-2023-51497. From here, using a public PoC script found on github, we are then able to leverage CVE-2023-49070 to get remote code execution and get a shell on the machine as the ofbiz user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Builder - HTB Writeup</title>
      <link>https://supaaasuge.github.io/posts/builder-htb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://supaaasuge.github.io/posts/builder-htb/</guid>
      <description>This post is a writeup for Medium difficulty Hack The Box machine: Builder. In this lab, we leverage CVE-2024-23897 a Local File Inclusion vulnerability to gather credentials for the user jennifer. From here, after logging into the Jenkins instance we use Jennifer&amp;rsquo;s account privileges to manually reset the root user&amp;rsquo;s password. Which then allowed us to view/edit the SSH key information. From there, we use the SSH key to easily log into the machine and get the root flag!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devvortex - HTB Writeup</title>
      <link>https://supaaasuge.github.io/posts/devvortex-htb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://supaaasuge.github.io/posts/devvortex-htb/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I go over the path I took towards getting root on the Hack The Box machine: Devvortex(Easy). As usual we start out with an nmap port scan, where we discover a Joomla site hosted on port 80. After finding the version of Joomla being used and looking for public exploits, I leverage CVE-2023-23752(Unauthenticated Information Disclosure) to get credentials to login as the user lewis. From here, we are able to edit templates on the site and add in a PHP reverse shell to get a foothold on the machine as www-data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
